Arlo J Purcell

4764 New River Road, 29576, Murrells Inlet, South Carolina US

I have a wide variety of experience in software, from point of sale software to natural language processing to global search engines. I have a drive to innovate, explore, solve interesting problems, and build great things.

SKILLS —		
Java	Python	Rust
Master	Master	Intermediate
Scala	Javascript	Kotlin
Scala	•	
Intermediate	Intermediate	Intermediate
Web Development		
Intermediate		
html css webassembly		
WORK EXPERIENCE (4)		

Staff Software Engineer at Indeed.com August 2014- Current

http://www.indeed.com

- Improved job posting javascript frontend using Closure library and compiler with soy template
- Added new features, fixed bugs, and improved performance on Java/Spring/Tomcat backend. The backend also used MySQL, MongoDB, and RabbitMQ
- Implemented and supported internal tooling for other engineers
- Created internal developer environment system using bash and python scripts around docker
- Maintained and improved internal deployment management webapp using a soy template with JQuery frontend and a Java/Spring/Tomcat backend interfacing with git and Gitlab and Atlassian APIs
- Proctored and graded coding exams for interview candidates
- Built a new system to aggregate data on code changes and then make automated merge decisions for continuous delivery
- Designed and implemented fast tool for querying, filtering, and caching production and QA logs
- Iteratively built and validated a new, caregiving job marketplace application as part of an internal incubator program
- Lead a team building a tool to build and execute data pipelines to convert application logs into queryable indices
- Wrote a custom expression language for processing data to build into indices
- Implemented fraud prevention and mitigation measures in candidate tracking system

Research and Development Engineer at IPsoft February 2013- August 2014

http://www.ipsoft.com

- Led a geographically separated team of developers in the creation of a new artificial intelligence system for human interaction, supported by relational and graph databases
- Estimated and assigned new features and bugs to my team
- Managed the project using agile methodologies

- Designed and implemented a first order logic engine for interpreting and then acting upon natural language
- Conceived and realized the machine learning system for dynamically creating and executing new business processes
- Fine tuned module for understanding, analyzing, and storing natural language, then generating natural language responses
- Demonstrated and explained the functionality and design of the system to high level executives at enterprise clients

Software Engineer at Google **February 2012- February 2013** https://www.google.com

- Developed library for deploying video ads in client applications
- Fixed bugs in Flash, Javascript, iOS, and Android versions of the library
- Designed and implemented an original new version of the Android library
- Created a new version of the library for Samsung smart TV
- Maintained and expanded unit and integration tests
- Managed public releases of the library
- Meticulously documented all code changes and new additions

Associate Applications Engineer at Micros Retail Systems August 2010- March 2012 http://www.microsnyc.com

- Developed Java point of sale application
- Developed and deployed iOS point of sale application
- Designed and implemented customer specific modifications
- Interfaced with customers to determine requirements for modifications and configurations
- Worked with quality assurance to resolve feedbacks

EDUCATION (1) —

Bachelor of Arts Computer Science at Oberlin College 2007 - 2010

Grade: 3.67